Alan Guttmacher Institute records SSC.MS.00720
Sophia Smith Collection
- Guttmacher Institute research files, staff files and project records, 2018-S-0052; 7.5 linear feet (6 record cartons)
  - 5 Year Plan files, 58 folders (58 folders)
    From the inventory sheet: "It is a bit difficult to pin down exactly which projects these files relate to. Many of the files relate to Title X and subsequent litigation. Some of the files relate to a project "Five Year Plan Family Planning Study." The dates of the files in these two boxes seem to range from the 1970s through the late 1980s."
    "Five Year Plan Family Planning Study" refers to multiple projects conducted for various organizations by the Guttmacher Institute, all iterations of the same core idea to study family planning through various lenses.
    - "Pop 81" population statistics and notes on race, poverty distribution, marital status, and income, plus programming information, 1980-1981; 6 folders (6 folders) (Box 5)
    - FY 1971 city and county study of family planning services and patterns (includes proposals, negotiations, questionnaires, study materials) (Box 5)
      From the questionnaire cover sheet: "This national survey is one part of a larger study which has been designed to: (a) estimate the number of women in need of subsidized family planning care and the number who received subsidized medical family planning services in fiscal year (FY) 1971; (b) identify the existing and potential resources for provision of family planning services; and (c) analyze the manpower utilization patterns of agencies which provide family planning services." The survey was conducted by the Guttmacher Institute in cooperation with the Council on Population of the American Public Health Association, the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, the American Hospital Association and the Association of State and Territorial Health Officers.
    - Family planning-related articles and reviews (including material by Joy G. Dryfoos), 1976-1980; 4 folders (4 folders) (Box 5)
    - Planned Parenthood court documents and relevant state bills, 1978-1986; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Guttmacher Title X background, memos, correspondence, and legal information, 1987-1991; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - NICHD (National Institute of Child Health and Human Development) family planning five-year plan evaluation and progress report, 1980-1981; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - DHHS (Department of Health and Human Services) family planning five-year plan contract, progress reports, methods, statistics, data, and analysis, 1980-1982; 15 folders (15 folders) (Box 6)
    - DHEW (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare) family planning five-year plan contracts, progress reports, relevant literature, technical proposals, and correspondence, 1976-1980; 7 folders (7 folders) (Box 6)
    - NCHS (National Center for Health Statistics) five-year plan proposal and budget, 1975; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Original inventory sheets, 2018; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)